Okay, let's see the Box Model here in our Web page.
So, I'm going to start the developers tools.
I'm going to "Inspect Element" here.
And for the Box Model,
this comes in the "Styles" pane
and should be in the "Layout" tab in Microsoft Edge.
So now, we're looking at
the Box Model for the body elements.
So for the body of the HTML page,
we can see there is a little bit of margin here.
There is no border and there
is no padding and the content of
the body is taking this amount of space.
So, I'm going to move on and focus on our list here.
For the list here,
you can see there is an offset,
some margin as well,
and there is some padding on the left and
there is the content of the list.
So I'm going to add a border for my list here.
My border is going to be...
I'm thinking 4 pixels solid style and green color.
So now, I see this around my list here.
So, if I go to check the Box Model for my list,
I see that now I have a border of
4 pixels on all sides.
We can change that, actually.
So let's make it a little bit thicker.
So it's 10 pixels from the top.
I can do the same for all sides of the border.
And you see that there is no padding.
I can add a little bit of padding, too,
and see what happens.
Margin also, we can like increase the margin or decrease
the margin and see how that's going
to like effect things on my page.
So let's put it back.
And that's it for this demo.
See you next time.