Hello, everyone. Today, I'd like to give you
a brief overview of a site called CodePen.
I'm already at the site here in my browser at codepen.io,
so you should browse there, too.
And here I am at the landing
page and I haven't logged in,
I don't have an account.
What I'm going to show you now is just a very brief
overview of what the site can be used for.
A "Pen" in this site is kind of like a Code snippet.
It's code you can write,
or you can also explore Pens that
the community has put up on the site for you to consume.
Let's start there, let's have a look at
what a Pen might look like.
To do that, I'm going over here on
the top right to the "Search" button,
and I get a nice big Search text box.
And if I just type in a term that I'm
interested in, for example, "Button",
and I just wait a brief second,
you'll see that that search returns 936,000 Pens.
So these are pieces of code that other people have
shared that contain something to do with Buttons,
the key word "Button".
And so, this is the list that you'll get back and you can
explore and do a lot of configuration on the search.
To see the code behind one of these,
you would click on the Tile that has been returned.
And I'll do it,
I'll click on this one.
And you can see an "Editor" opens up,
and it has a HTML Pane, A CSS Pane,
a JavaScript Pane,
and an Output Pane. This is just an example.
We won't go into the code in this example.
But you can see that this is a live preview of what's
being shown here from
the code out down here below in the Output window.
So let's go back. That was just an example of a Pen
that someone else has created and
they've decided to share it publicly.
Why don't we try and create our first Pen?
To do that, we're going to come
over to the "Create" button here.
Click on "New Pen". And you'll
notice I still haven't logged in.
I'm just using the site as a public visitor.
So I click on "New Pen" and an empty editor opens up.
You can see the three panes HTML, CSS and JavaScript.
Nice big output panel here down in the bottom.
Don't like this view?
Go ahead and "Change view",
and you can reconfigure it to have editors on the left,
the editors on the right, et cetera.
Now, I'll just stick to the "Default view".
Also, only going to code some HTML, so here,
I'm going to "Maximize the
HTML editor" which slides the others
out of view of a nice lot of space here to work with.
To save some time, let's just paste in some HTML.
What you see here is that the preview is live, as in,
when I make a change in my code,
it shows up in the output practically instantaneously,
which is a really great feature.
Let's change the code to watch it in action.
So, I'm going to change my code "Hello CodePen!"
I'm going to wrap it in a header, H1 header,
and we should see that text
get larger in the output panel.
So I put in my tag,
and you can see
that it's actually expanded which is great.
The other nifty little features that you can use here:
if you get HTML into a state you're not happy
with how it looks on the screen,
you can say "Tidy HTML".
And we'll try to indent a little bit better
and spread it out so that it's more readable.
Even go as far as going into the
"Settings" and under "Behavior",
use "Tabs" over "Spaces".
So that's a nice feature.
So that's the code editing part of CodePen.
And I encourage you, if you don't want to download
a tool or other editors,
you can browse here for free and write
some code and see it appear in the Output window.
Take other people's code and play with it.
Explore with their cool creations
and try that stuff out as well.
Another reason I wanted to introduce CodePen is,
because if you look at our course,
you may come across this editor here in line,
inside the content that we've created.
It's an embedded CodePen editor.
In this example, it shows you two panes,
the "HTML" code and the "Result".
Switch off the "Result"and just show
the "HTML" by clicking on the "Result" button.
Vice versa. I can also edit inline here.
So for example, if I go into this paragraph
in code and I say something like "Hi!",
that will refresh, on the right hand side,
the actual output, which is interesting.
I'll just ignore that DOCTYPE warning for the moment.
That's not really important right now.
This is a live editing experience
embedded into our course,
but you can go over to CodePen which is where we've been,
and you can navigate to the actual Pen that was created.
And here, you can see that in the CodePen site.
And you get yourself an account on CodePen.
You're able to do stuff like just fork this,
which is effectively copying
this actual Pen into
your own account so you can play with it,
use it, and so on, and so forth.
That's the round tripping. I just
wanted to make sure you see.
When you come across these integers inside our course,
you'll know that that's really
a CodePen editor inside the content,
that you can then go and use the CodePen site,
or use it directly inside the content itself.
So that's it. A very quick look at
the popular online editor and
front-end code playground called CodePen.
Until next time, happy coding.